Patrick Naish

Physical contact details available on request

patrick@pmnaish.co.uk

Personal statement

Currently in my third year at Southampton University. I am a Software Engineering MEng (http://www.ecs.soton.ac.uk/programmes/g600-meng-software-engineering-4-yrs) student with an interest in software design and security. I have a large amount of experience working in development groups, both within university work and in my own projects.

Qualifications

Course/qualification MEng Software Engineering	Dates from and to 2010-present	Education institution University of Southampton	Grade TBC
A2 Mathematics A2 Further Mathematics	2009-2010 2009-2010	St. Bartholomew's School, Newbury	A* C
A2 Computing A2 Physics GCSEs	2009-2010 2009-2010 2006-2008		A B A*-B

So far on my course, I have taken modules in:

- Programming Principles
- Advanced Programming
- Discrete Mathematics for Computer Science
- Introduction to Formal Methods
- Digital Electronics
- Data Structures and Algorithms
- Software Engineering
- System Administration Tools and Techniques
- Computational Systems
- Human-Computer Interaction
- Software Analysis and Design
- Operating Systems
- Theory of Computing
- Professional and Legal Issues
- Principles of Computer Graphics
- Scripting Languages
- Hypertext and Web Technologies
- Management 1
- Database Systems
- Distributed Computing
- Communications and Networks
- Compiler Engineering
- Software Engineering Group Project
- Artificial Intelligence
- Computer Architecture
- Personal and Professional Development
- Engineering Maths for Computer Science

In the first vear of mv Software Engineering course I averaged a 1st overall. In mv second vear I averaged fractionally under a 1st. My third year, including a large individual development project, is progressing well so far.

Skills acquired

- A diagnosis of Asperger's Syndrome when I was 13 years old lead to me self-teaching my GCSEs, during which time I developed strong self-discipline and utilised my desire to learn to obtain my grades from A*-A, and one B.
- Working at the Newbury Library for several years has helped me to develop good interpersonal skills, and experience of handling sensitive data securely.
- My summer work at IBM Hursley gave me an insight into the workings of a software company, and an awareness of the teamworking skills and processes that are required in such an environment.
- My summer internship at Micro Focus gave me experience in working in a SCRUM team, with development in an OSGi framework.

Key skills and achievements

- My first programming language was C, which I started about 9 years ago.
- I am a reasonably strong Java developer, having several modules over the first and second years of my course that teach Java coding and best practices. I have also gained some experience in working with Jetty webservers and the OSGi framework.
- I can program in r5rs Scheme, thanks to my Computational Systems module.
- I did 2 weeks of summer work at the IBM Hursley Lab, during which time I helped to debug an internal Extreme Blue project (LogWeaver).
- I participated in the DevXS event (devxs.org), in which we were challenged to create a web application that provided a service to students. This was done in a group, over 29 hours, using Python. In our group, we created intr (intr.ep.io), which is a framework for society managements at university. This is currently being developed into a full system known as Treehouse (website pending).
- I am currently in a group of developers who are creating Owings (owin.gs), a system for managing group expenses. This is helping me to gain experience in Ruby and Rails, as well as general web development.
- I learned a significant amount of Javascript, including the dojo framework, during my internship at Micro Focus.

Employment history

Job title Volunteer Summer Library Volunteer Sunday Library Assistant Owings Developer Summer Intern	Dates Summer 2008 Summers 2009, 2010, 2011 25/04/2010 – 27/06/2010 January 2012 – ongoing June 2012 - September 2012	Company/Team name West Berkshire Mencap West Berkshire Libraries West Berkshire Libraries Team Owin.gs Micro Focus UK
Christmas Intern	December 2012	Micro Focus UK

Interests

Computer and system security, web applications, software development process.

Referees

Available on request.